Curriculum Vitae

Michael L. Schott

Phone: (520) 477-7956

Email: schottml@email.arizona.edu

Department of Physics University of Arizona 1118 E. 4th Street, PO Box 210081 Tucson, AZ 85721

Research Statement

Current research interests focus on learning data analysis techniques and modern machine learning architectures as well as cloud and distributed computing frameworks as tools for investigating physics problems in novel ways. Fields of study most appealing are High Energy physics and the study of Complex Systems, both of which have many unanswered questions and hold the promise of revealing new and interesting truths about our universe.

Education

| 2012 – 2016 | University of Cincinnati B.S. in Physics, April, 2016 |
|----------------|---|
| 2012 – 2016 | University of Cincinnati B.A. in Mathematics, April, 2016 |
| 2016 – Present | University of Arizona Ph.D in Physics, <i>Expected: 2021</i> |

Research

| Fall 2016 | Dr. John Schaibley, Independent Study University of Arizona, Department of Physics |
|-----------|---|
| Fall 2017 | Dr. Kaitlin Kratter, Independent Study University of Arizona, Astronomy Department |
| Fall 2018 | Dr. Kenneth Johns, Graduate Assistant University of Arizona, Department of Physics |

Teaching

University of Arizona

Spring 2018 Teaching Assistant, Physics 141 & Physics 241D

Department of Physics

Michael L. Schott

Fall 2017 Teaching Assistant, Physics 182

Department of Physics

Spring 2017 Teaching Assistant, Physics 181

Department of Physics

Fall 2016 Teaching Assistant, Physics 181

Department of Physics

University of Cincinnati

2013 – 2016 Peer Tutor, Physics and Mathematics

Learning Assistance Center

Other Positions

Spring 2018 – Present Publicity Officer of Women in Physics

Fall 2017 – Present Officer of Physics Department Graduate Student Council

Fall 2017 – Present Member of Women in Physics

Publications

Refereed Journals

1) Rachit Malik, Lu Zhang, Colin McConnell, **Michael Schott**, Yu-Yun Hsieh, Ryan Noga, Noe Alvarez, Vesselin Shanov. (2017). "Three-dimensional, free-standing polyaniline/carbon nanotube composite-based electrode for high-performance supercapacitors". *Carbon*. 116. 10.1016/j.carbon.2017.02.036.